S. K. GURUCHAL

Mumbai-421 503

Contact: +91 8097 162931, +91 9987 220634

Email: swap_guru@rediffmail.com, Skype: swapnil.guruchal

Objective:-

9 years of experience in the field of **Piping Execution/Inspection/ Operation Offshore & Onshore (Shipbuilding/ Marine/ Rig/ Oil & Gas/ Fertilizer/Refinery) Industries.** To be successful professional in the highly competitive field of Mechanical engineering. To learn and master the ever-evolving technologies through hard work, dedication and total commitment.

Professional Experience: -8.9 Years.

- Working as Crude Storage Tank & Piping Engineer with Chemie- Tech
 DMCC, Nigeria. 25 TH July 2017 to Till Now.
- Worked as Asst. Manager -Piping Engineer with Onshore Construction LLC,
 Nigeria. 14TH June 2016 to 16TH June 2017.
- Worked as Piping Engineer with Vedam Design & Technology Centre,
 Mumbai, India.6[™] December 2012 to 13 [™] June 2016.
- Worked as Assistant Engineer Piping with Bharati Shipyard Pvt. Ltd,
 Ratnagiri, India, 1ST January 2011 To 5TH December 2012.
- Worked as Design Engineer Piping with Varsha Engineering Services,
 Thane, India, 1ST June 2009 To 31ST December 2010.

Educational Qualifications:-

- B.E. in Mechanical Engineering, Mumbai University.
- Diploma in Mechanical Engineering, Maharashtra Board of Technical Education.
- S.S.C, Board of Secondary Education.

Work Experience:-

Chemie- Tech DMCC, Abu Dhabi. July 2017 - Till Now.

Engineer - Crude Storage Tank & Piping Engineer - Dangote Refinery Plant.

- Having extensive experience in non-metallic & metallic piping, both inspection and construction.
- Expertise in making, checking, approving piping drawings like isometrics, layouts, support drawing, and expert in the inspection & construction as well.
- Visual inspection of bare pipe for defects, flats, oil. Verification of Pipe No. Heat No., Length, Preheating Temperature before Blasting. Ambient Conditions, Degree of Cleanliness.
- Holiday Test for defects & damages, Cut back Length measure. & Bevel Angle (to ensure), Marking of Accepted Pipe, Total Thickness Inspection.
 - Site Execution, Pipe rack, Equipment, Pumps piping construction.
- Inspection of Fabrication, Erection & Hydro testing of Piping System as per P &ID, G.A.
 - Verification of testing certificate of item code product before use in operation.
 - Offer the job before finalizing to owner representative for final approval.
 - Job involves coordination effectively with consultants for Engineering,

procurement and inspection and also with construction team.

- Extensive coordination will have to be done between engineering office and vendor during ordering, drawing review and issue at site.
- Planning, scheduling & will have to report periodically the daily progress of project to project In charge management.
 - Project:
- o Dangote Refinery Project. Nigeria

Onshore Construction Pvt. Ltd. Jun 2016 - Jun 2017.

Asst. Manager - Piping - Dangote Fertilizer Plant.

- Preparation/ review of equipment layouts, piping GAD/isometrics, Piping supports and specifications. MTO, 3D Plant Models. Review of DCA.
- Co-ordination with other departments. Communication with customer/ clients & participation in technical discussions with customer
- Co-ordination with Erection and commissioning for site support. Provide the proper solution in critical situation for piping fabrication & execution team.
- Design effective, cost-efficient and innovative engineering solutions to meet client needs.

Ensure to meet scheduled commitments. Identify and prioritize scope specific initiatives.

- Project:
- o Dangote Fertilizer Project. Nigeria

Vedam Design and Technology Pvt. Ltd. Dec 2012 - Jun 2016

Piping Engineer - Ship building, Oil and Gas, Rig plant

- Ensuring engineering work undertaken is accordance with Procedures and Standards. Review technical specifications for shipboard equipment, technical review of quotations, and preparation of trial procedure.
- Review drawings/ equipment specification and check whether they are meeting all rules/ standards/ statutory requirements applicable for the project.
- Worked in coordination with the project administrator and managers to complete the projects Served as a point of contact from project initiation to completion.
 - Inspection of piping layout as per P & ID. Checking the construction as the reference of G.A.
 - Responsible for Hull/ Outfitting/ Structural & piping inspection & witness.
 - Dry inspection, painting inspection before basine & se trial.
 - Pre- commissioning check up, & commissioning as witness approval.
- Allocated resources to various departments and managers as per their needs and requirements.
- Analysed and monitored the project reports to sort out issues in documentation section.
- Maintained and documented reports on a daily basis regarding the projects assigned to various departments; progress, schedule, budgeting and forecasting
- Checking of all Hull structure, Piping arrangement, GA, Painting Spec, Piping Spec during fabrication.
- Commissioning of pumps related systems, Main Engine, D.G. Set, and Safety Alarms. Basin Trial, Sea Trials. &solving the technical queries regarding design on site carefully.
- Technically solve the quires on site, surveying of ship's hull, piping, alignment, painting, routing of pipes, erection & commissioning of system. Oil/Gas/ Rig piping.
 - Ensure that the Safety, Quality & Environment requirements of the yard are
 - Project:
 - o 1400T INLAND OIL BARGE-1
 - o 1400T INLAND OIL BARGE-2.

Bharati Shipyard Pvt. Ltd.

Dec 2010 - Dec 2012

Assistant Engineer - Piping (Layout & Execution).

Piping Design

- Process Plant Layout Piping Basic & Detail Design engineering for interconnecting Equipment's like Distillation Towers, Pumps, Heat Exchangers, Compressors, Reactors, Storage Tanks, Drums, Pipe-Racks.
- Piping Study layout with reference of Plot-Plan, Process P&ID, Utility P&ID, Line-List, Civil Drawing, Piping Specification, Equipment Data sheet, Instrument specification, etc. to identify location for equipment's and associated infrastructure for routing the piping to satisfy client specifications for operational, maintenance & safety requirement and considering the possibility of piping supports.
- Design Equipment layout, Equipment arrangement & Elevation, Nozzle orientation, Platform Elevation, ladder & staircase arrangement, hand railing
- Preparation of layout as per suitable at site, Erection of machinery, Fabrication and Erection of piping, penetration, support etc.
- Pre-commissioning checks as per drawing, cold check of Piping, testing, Commissioning of piping system
- For Special type vessels having Fire Fighting, DNV, LRS, IRS & BV class approved.
- Supervise the job for the fabrication and fitment of pipe, valves, pumps, filter, heat exchanger, and varies piping equipment Supervise the project execution work as per design.
- As per class requirement showing system operational performance to surveyor and owner such as all the alarm, monitoring & safety functions and working of equipment as per trial protocol.
- Preparing inventory for material indents. Material inspection & Maintain MVR
- Project:
 - V/356 BOURBON ARGOS-LUXEMBOURG [AHT VESSEL].
 - o V/381 UP JADE, BAHAMA.
 - o V/395 SCI-HEERA [AHT VESSEL].
 - o V/394 SCI-MUKTA [AHT VESSEL].

Certifications:-

PDS, SP3D, Piping Modelling, AutoCAD 2D, Solid works, CNC Programming (Coding & Operation)

Reference:

- Mr.V.S.Bagave, DGM QA/QC Piping, Hull, Bharati Shipyard Ltd. India: +919421230997.
- Mr. P. Chattopadhyay, VP, VDTC & Pipavav Shipyard Ltd. India: +919727777120.

Personal Details:-

Permanent Address : Flat No. B/204, Yashwant Complex,

Near KatrapVidyalay, Katrap, Badlapur (E.), Thane-421 503,

Maharashtra, India 13th march. 1986.

 Date of Birth
 : 13th march, 1986

 Passport No.
 : H7066740.

 Passport Date Issue.
 : 13 /11 /2009.

 Passport Date Exp.
 : 12 /11 /2019.

I hereby declare that all the information provided in this application is factual and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

S. K. GURUCHAL.